<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pugdundee Safaris</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="drawerOpen">open</string>
    <string name="drawerClose">close</string>
    <string name="mainMenuTitle">Pugdundee Safaris is recognized as one of India\'s leading responsible safari companies. With six intimate jungle lodges in Central India, one in Chitwan - Nepal and many bespoke wilderness experiences it presents the very best of the Indian subcontinent wildlife &amp; hospitality. Between 2010 and 2016, we have been awarded for our excellence in eco-tourism, our commitment to green architecture, our experienced naturalists and our pioneering mobile safari initiative.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lodges">Lodges</string>
    <string name="kingsLodgeDescrip">Kings Lodge is nestled between Sal forested hills of Bandhavgarh National Park in a large natural forested estate of 14 hectares in a small tribal village. The lodge is in the heart of the Tiger country and only a ten minutes drive from the Tala gate of the national park. Our guests benefit from our incredible location, outstanding hospitality, an experienced naturalist team, our commitment towards conservation and local communities. The lodge has 10 cottage rooms and 8 stilt cottage rooms with en-suite modern bathrooms spread across a natural forest offering great ambience and privacy.</string>
    <string name="treeHouseDescrip">Tree House Hideaway - On and among the trees in our five tree houses there is a route to hide away of fantasies. In the 21 acres area of forest rests an option of experiencing the snug life inside the rooms or venture out in the tiger-infested wild. The property has its resident species of birds, reptiles and animals residing around the forest trees and over time the area has now become a small secure park for them. You can spend your time unseen and undisturbed in the intimacy of your room or choose to go looking for wild animals &amp; birds in Bandhavgarh Tiger Reserve.\n\n

                                    In the wild world of Bandhavgarh Tiger Reserve, the outlook of tree houses is grunge and sturdy looking but the door opens to acceptable elegance complementing the outside world. The designs are a fetching fusion of contemporary design and traditional jungle living with earth tones and eco essentials. All Tree houses have been made by local staff using regularized wood. Local craft knowledge and traditional expertise has been used at all quarters to ensure that the Tree Houses blend harmoniously with nature.</string>
    <string name="kahnaDescrip">Kanha Earth Lodge is spread in 16 acres of natural forest, tucked away in a small hamlet bordering Kanha’s buffer zone. Its unique location, 30 minutes from the Khatia/Kisli park gate, ensures that it is close enough for easy access to the park, but still far enough from the glut of hotels lining Kanha’s tourist hub to offer guests a true wilderness experience. The 12 luxury bungalows with large open verandahs have been inspired by Gond tribal architecture and offer environmentally sensitive, low-impact accommodation through their design and use of local stone and waste wood. While the absence of neighbouring lodges or highways creates an ideal setting for nature walks, birding and cycling trips through the surrounding forest.</string>
    <string name="kenriverDescrip">Ken River Lodge made a humble start in 1986 - one of the pioneers of wildlife tourism in the country. Driven by passion for wildlife and conservation encouraged Shyamendra Singh, grandson of Maharaja of Nagod to establish the lodge. The lodge has been washed out twice in the floods of 1992 and 2007 but has been rebuilt with the same zeal and passion. The lodge is set in a forested estate of 50 acres and has been built with natural materials sourced mostly from neighboring villages and surrounding areas. The forested estate is home to many mammals, birds and reptiles.\n\n

                                    The Accommodation is simple and rustic with few mod cons thrown in. The 6 huts and 6 cottages are spread out in a mixed jungle in undulating terrain, giving a jungle experience which few in the country can parallel. The lodge also boasts of a 3000 sq.ft. Machaan were the meals are served. The machaan popularly known as the Tree House overlooks the Ken River and offers fresh home cooked meals.</string>
    <string name="penchDescrip">The famous Jungle Book character Mowgli was a wolf befriending boy from the tribal village of Pench. If Mowgli could enliven his escapades, Pench tree lodge would be his time warped home in 21st century. He could certainly somersault with the monkeys here or luxuriously laze under the shade of Mahua Tree, in the comforts of stylish, spacious and snugly tree houses set in regal landscapes. Later, deciding to set out on a Jeep Safari to meet ‘Shere Khan’–the Tiger and ‘Baloo’-the Bear and check on his troop of ‘Bander log’– monkey folks and all other good old friends from Pench national park.\n\n

Pench Tree Lodge is the refuge of the au courant, adventurous and eco sensitive ‘Mowgli’. Our six well appointed tree houses are perched in the undisturbed 16 hectares of forested area in the small ‘Sarrahiri’ village of Pench in the Karmajhiri area. This is the first lodge to be set up in this underdeveloped zone and supports are conservation policy of not overcrowding areas and making them unsustainable with over exposure to tourism.</string>
    <string name="barahiDescrip">Barahi Jungle Lodge insinuates the austerity of Chitwan National Park. Experiencing refined luxury in the panoramic savannahs punctuated by Rapti River as overlooked from Barahi’s vantage point is a parallel universe retreat. We take immense pride in strengthening the bond of nature and mankind through our itineraries. The ambient outlook and sort after interiors of the lodge give a stunning insight into the aboriginal Tharu culture of Nepal interlaced with wilderness of Chitwan.\n\n

The lodge is nestled in a forested patch of 12 hectares and the construction is inspired by the local Tharu villages. It blends effortlessly with the surrounding environment and sets a high standard in eco operations.\n\n

The lodge has an in house experienced team of naturalists, 4 private elephants and a fleet of jeeps &amp; boats. The lodge is strategically located in Meghauli, west Chitwan considered the best area for viewing wildlife.\n\n</string>
    <string name="title_activity_parks">Parks</string>
    <string name="park_pench_descrip">Pench National Park is a wild playground harboring country’s maximum density of prey animals, chased by an estimated 65 Tigers. The park is well administered and extensively mentioned in the Indian history for its vivid fauna and flora. The landscapes of scrublands, deciduous forest of Teaks and many lakes, streams and Pench River can be instantly associated with the incidents and wild mentions of the animal life in the jungle book of Sir Rudyard Kipling. The established corridor between Pench and Kanha National park, adds to the glory of both the parks with many animals frequently traversing between the park boundaries. Pench is a protected area in the southern extensions to the hills of Satpura, Central India and park was established in 1975, subsequently declared a tiger reserve, Kanha-Pench Tiger Conservation unit under Project tiger in 1992.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_programs">Programs</string>
    <string name="title_activity_photos_view">Photo Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_contact_us">Contact Us</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="aboutUsMain">Pugdundee is a hindi word meaning a foot trail commonly used by humans and animals, this word is popularly used for such beaten paths in the Indian jungles.\n\n

Driven by the love of Indian jungles it made an unplanned humble beginning in 1986, with a small tented camp at Panna - Ken River Lodge. Between 2007 -2010 two more lodges were setup and it was not until the year 2010 that they all were put together under a common umbrella.\n\n

Today Pugdundee Safaris is run by a passionate team of wildlifers and hospitality professionals with a team of over 300 people committed in providing an incredible wildlife experience. The team includes naturalists, nature Guides, mahouts, boat men, trackers and a marketing team based in Delhi.\n\n

Besides its mainstay of running wildlife lodges, Pugdundee Safaris has been keenly engaged in conservation and community development activities which is now looked after by Pugdundee Conservation Cell founded in 2010. At Pugdundee we believe local people hold the future of the forests in their hands and can either help protect or destroy them. If we wish to conserve our forests, we must look after the needs of local people by helping to improve their ability to earn livelihoods, which in turn will help to enhance their standards of living. Addressing their needs is the key to ensuring the future of our natural habitats.\n\n

Our lodges set mostly in remote locations away from regular tourism hubs help ensure that the benefit of eco tourism is distributed far and beyond.\n\n

We continuously strive to deliver the best possible guest experience, while still integrating the conservation of jungles and the people living around. We are inspired by the hope of reaching people in remotest areas of our country as they are the front runners of wildlife conservation. Though a drop in the ocean we believe we are making a significant contribution to wildlife conservation and the rural economy wherever our lodges are.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_book_now">BookNow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash_screen">SplashScreen</string>
    <string name="park_kahna_descrip">Kanha Tiger Reserve is spread over an area of 1,949 sq km (940 sq km of core area and 1,009 sq km of buffer zone), making it one of the best habitats for tigers in India. The park is situated in the Central Indian Highlands, which are part of the extensive tableland that forms India’s main peninsula. Kanha’s undulating landscape is dotted with dense groves of vegetation, hillocks and meadows. Of all these habitats, it is Kanha’s meadows that are its lifeline, as they sustain large numbers of Chital, Sambar, Barasingha and Gaur, which in turn support populations of predators and co-predators (Tigers, Leopards, Wild Dogs, Jungle Cats and Foxes). The park is primarily a moist Sal and moist mixed deciduous forest featuring Sal, Bamboo, Tendu, Jamun, Arjun and Lendia. It is home to over 1,000 species of flowering plants and about 350 species of birds.\n\n

Its greatest achievement has been the preservation of Hard Ground Swamp Deer or Barasingha from near extinction (they numbered just 66 in 1970). Today, they number more than 400 and are the only surviving population of Barasingha in the wild.</string>
     <string name="park_panna_descrip">Panna National Park spread over 543 sq km was carved out of the hunting reserves of the erstwhile Panna, Chattarpur and Bijawar states. Panna was accorded sanctuary status in 1975 and upgraded to a national park in 1981. In 1994, it became India’s 22nd Tiger Reserve. Panna is situated at the junction of the Gangetic plains and the Deccan peninsula. The panna hills provide the catchment area for the Ken River, which is the life line of the park.\n\n

It is predominantly an open forest, offering great opportunity to see the Tiger and other mammals. It also supports closed canopy forests, open forest with short grass and undercover, open Savannah woodlands which reflect sub Saharan habitats, tall grasslands and degraded scrub. \n\n

Panna has been home to a highly successful Tiger relocation project. From near extinction the Tiger population has reached a healthy figure of 35. </string>
    <string name="park_satpura_descrip">Satpura is a Sanskrit word, that means seven mountains (sapta=seven &amp; pura=mountain). Most of the Satpura range was heavily forested, but the area has been subject to gradual deforestation in recent decades, although significant stands of forests remain. These forest enclaves provide habitat to several at risk and endangered species, including the Tiger.\n\n

Satpura National Park is one the areas of this landscape preserved marvelously for protection of flora and fauna.\n\n

Satpura National Park is spread over 1427 sq km and was formed in 1981 after joining Satpura, Pachmari and Bori sanctuaries and the altitude ranges from 300 to 1,352 metres (980 to 4,436 ft). The terrain of the national park is extremely rugged and consists of fascinating deep valleys, sandstone peaks, narrow gorges, rivulets, waterfalls, thick dense green forest of Sal and other medicinal herbs, it also has large tracts of Teak forests.\n\n

Its fauna comprises Spotted Dear, Indian Bison(Gaur), Tigers, Leopards, Wild boar, Wild dog (locally called Dholes), Sloth bear, Black buck (unique attraction), Porcupine, Sambhar, Four Horned antelopes (Chowsingha), Otters, Crocodile, Malabar squirrels, Langurs etc.\n\n

Indian Giant squirrel and White Bison are a special feature of Satpura National Park. It offers good birding opportunity due to its unique terrain and many water bodies including the Tawa reservoir. From November to March it also hosts a variety of migratory birds in the Tawa reservoir and fields around the park </string>
    <string name="park_bandhv_descrip">Bandhavgarh was established in 1968 as a National Park, and is spread over an area of 1150 sq. kms. This national park was declared as a tiger reserve under Project Tiger in the year 1993. It is predominantly covered with vegetation like SAL, SALI, DHOBIN and has vast stretches of grasslands spread over 32 hills, the region though smaller than other wildlife parks has one of the highest density of tigers in the world. Bandhavgarh was earlier the hunting reserve of the Maharajas of Rewa, the region was a major hunting ground of animals where Maharaja Raman Singh himself shot a stupendous figure of 111 tigers by 1914. Bandhavgarh also became world renowned for its population of rare white tigers.\n\n

The historical links of Bandhavgarh are to be found in India’s worshipped mythological heroes Rama and Laxmana. The name “bandhav-garh” translates to “the brother’s fort” and believed to be gifted by Hindu God Rama to his devoted ‘bandhav’ (brother) Laxmana on his return from victory over Lanka (Ceylon). Inside the park there are 12 natural waterholes, several other historical monuments and remains of ancient caves that exhibit a 2000 year old rich historical past.\n\n

The vegetation is chiefly of Sal forest in the valleys and on the lower slopes, gradually changing to mixed deciduous forest on the hills and in the hotter drier areas of the park in the south and west. The wide valleys along the streams carry long linear grasslands flanked by Sal forests. Rich mixed forests consisting of Sal (shorea rubusta), Saja, Salai, and Dhobin etc. with dense bamboo thickets occur in many places. These together provide Bandhavgarh its rich biodiversity.\n\n

With the tiger at the apex of the food chain, it contains 37 species of mammals, more than 250 species of birds, about 70 species of butterflies, a number of reptiles.</string>
    <string name="park_chitwan_descrip">Chitwan National Park is a UNESCO protected World Heritage Site which was designated as a national Park in 1973. The park is world renowned for Rhino sightings in great numbers. With mixed vegetation of Savannah, Riverine and Sal forest, Chitwan is Nepal’s most visited National Park and a haven for wild life aficionados. Four of the Big Five can be seen (Rhinos, Tigers, Leopards and Asiatic Elephants) along with a rich population of 4 types of Deer, Wild Boars, Marsh Muggars and Ghariyals. Due to its closeness to Himalayan circuit the park also shelters winter and summer migrants along with its more than 500 native bird species. Chitwan is a bird watcher’s paradise - indigenous and migrant species like Great Hornbill, Ruddy Shelduck, Pied Kingfisher and Red Headed Trogon can also be found. Strict conservation policies and military patrolling have decimated poaching incidents and the park has been showing a growth in the Rhino Population.\n\n

Chitwan is a hindi word formed by two independent words Chit and Van translating to “heart of the jungle”. The shape of the park is largely dictated by the disposition of the three rivers which form much of the boundaries- the Narayani and Rapti in the north, and the Reu flowing through the National Park. The topography and variety of habitats- savannahs, riverine from valleys, sal of the hills and chir pine along the ridges contribute to the forest’s beauty and complexity.</string>
</resources>
